♪ 我的站到了 ♪
♪ This is my stop ♪
♪ 得下车了 ♪
♪ Got to get off ♪
♪ 还敢更挤嘛 ♪
♪ I might go pop ♪
借过
Excuse me
♪ 原谅我这么直 ♪
♪ I've got to be direct ♪
♪ 如冒犯请指教 ♪
♪ If I'm off, please correct ♪
♪ 你挡着我道了 ♪
♪ You're standing on my neck ♪
拽妹Daria
漫迪字幕组倾情奉献
——·旗木译制·——
Mack 写一下"男生就是这个星球苦难的源泉"
Mack, make that "boys are the scourge of the Earth."
男生不许在课堂上嚼口香糖
《泄密的心》? 我超爱言情小说
The Telltale Heart? I love romance novels!
神秘及幻想故事集
是啊 没什么比暗恋中的砰然之心更能表达"我要你"了
Yeah, nothing says "be mine" like a pounding heart beneath a floorboard.
注意了 年轻人们
Attention, young people.
我要宣布个激动人心的消息
I have an exciting announcement.
格鲁夫希尔 专收天赋异禀及优秀学生的学校
Grove Hills, the school for gifted and outstanding students,
已向我校发出邀请 请我们的几位同学过去参观
has issued invitations to several of our students to visit its campus.
这几位有幸的同学分别是:
And among those so honored are:
Morgendorffer同学和Landon同学
Ms. Morgendorffer and Ms. Landon.
我就知道数学一路得了及格是福不是祸
I knew those straight Cs in math would pay off some day.
破盘子
Damn plate!
嘿 妈妈跟我说格鲁夫希尔访问的事了 有你的 小鬼
Hey, mom told me about Grove Hills. That's great, kiddo!
是啊
Yeah.
我厌倦待在一个所有孩子都觉得他们比我酷的学校了
I'm tired of being at a school where the kids just think they're cooler than me.
我想去一个他们也觉得自己比我聪明的学校
I want to go to one where they think they're smarter than me also.
Daria 太为你骄傲了 亲爱的
Daria, I'm so proud of you, honey.
格鲁夫希尔
Grove Hills.
在那里认识的朋友会切实有助于你的前途
The friends you make there could really launch your career.
周末应该上网 干嘛要去上学?
And why study when you can network?
只是去参观下 Daria
It's just a visit, Daria.
当初他们也是这么跟肯尼迪说的
That's what they told J.F.K.
给你20块钱
I'll pay you $20.
一百
A hundred.
嘿 你怎么从来都不贿赂我?
Hey! How come you never offer me a bribe?
因为我们俩是一伙儿的
Because we work together as a team.
我来搞定这死丫头
Now, let me handle this.
该死
Darn it.
给你20块钱 我来搞定行吗?
If I give you $20 will you let me handle this?
一百
A hundred.
- 四十 - 六十
- Forty. - Sixty.
- 五十 - 成交
- Fifty. - Done.
- 五十? - 成交
- Fifty? - Done.
那就这么定了
Then it's settled.
我们这周末去格鲁夫希尔中学
We're going to Grove Hills this weekend.
他们圈养那些学霸怪咖的地方吗?
That place where they fence in all the geeks?
干嘛我也得去啊? 讲不讲理啊?
Why do I have to go? That's not fair!
Quinn 恐怕姐妹什么的没被邀请呢
Quinn, I'm afraid siblings aren't invited.
你就留在家里
You're staying home.
你是说全家人都出去玩只留下我?
You mean the whole family gets to go without me?
讲不讲理啊?
That's not fair!
给你
Oh, here.
不用担心 你们不在的时候我会好好照看家里的
Don't worry, I'll take good care of the house while you're gone.
你是说像上次那样 在家里开小酒桶派对
You mean like last time, when you had that keg party
Jeffy还在老妈的橱柜里吐了?
and Jeffy threw up in Mom's closet?
人家才没 是Jerome
He did not. It was Jerome.
不管是谁 我还是不太倾向让你一人在家
I don't like the idea of you staying here alone, anyway.
怎么? 我又不害怕
Why? I'm not afraid.
是啊 你有毛可害怕的?
Yeah. Why should you be afraid?
怕大屠杀凶手 连环杀手 虐待狂 食人族...
Of mass murderers, serial killers, torturers, cannibals...
虐狗狂?
puppy kickers?
老妈
Muh-om!
不如你去Sandi家吧
Maybe you can stay at Sandi's.
我豁出去给那个Linda巫婆打个电话
Even if I have to call that witch, Linda.
Linda? 还好吗?
Linda? How are you?
我刚刚达成了今年目标业绩的120%
Well, I just made 120% of my target projection for this year,
拿到了红利和一张激励支票
earning me a bonus and an incentive check,
所以特么好爆了 你呢?
so I'm pretty damn good. How you?
我今年过得也蛮好的
Um, I'm having a good year, too.
对 今年蛮好 没错
Yes, a very good year. Yes.
太谢谢你让Quinn这周末去你家了
Uh, thank you so much for letting Quinn stay with you this weekend.
听着 这孩子偶尔需要家长监督下
Now, she sometimes needs a little supervision...
别担心 我有严格的基本家法
Don't worry. I've got firm ground rules.
第一点也是最重要的 男孩免进
First and foremost: no boys.
绝对免进
N-O, no.
Sandi会用棍子把他们都打跑
Sandi has to beat them off with a stick.
我在开什么玩笑?
Who am I kidding?
我在她这个年纪也总惦记臭小子
I had the same problem at her age.
Ricky和其他男生会在塔尖街等着咱们
So, Ricky and the guys will be waiting for us at Tower Point.
抹防污口红
Wear smudge-proof lipstick.
我已经把车钥匙藏起来了 以防她有二心
I've already hidden the keys to the car, in case Sandi gets any ideas.
话说我以前也拿棍子打过他们来着
You know, I used to have to beat them off with a stick, too.
我早就又配了一把车钥匙了
I made a copy of the keys to the car.
戴上围巾 以免发型乱了
Bring scarf to avoid convertible hair.
十一点必须熄灯
And lights out by 11:00.
听我说没? 我也拿棍子打跑过男孩
Did you hear that? About the stick?
等十一点我妈查完房以后
Then, after my mother checks on us at 11:00,
我们就从窗户跑出去 开上车 去见那帮男生
we climb out my window, grab the car, and meet the guys.
天呐 Sandi 你想的真是万无一失
Boy, Sandi, you've thought of everything.
怪不得你是时尚俱乐部的主席呢
No wonder you're president of the Fashion Club.
天呐 Linda 你想的真是万无一失
My, Linda, you've thought of everything.
怪不得你能加入朗岱尔女企业家联盟呢
No wonder you're on the board of the Lawndale Businesswoman's Alliance.
多谢载我
Thanks for the ride.
我爸妈会在他们俱乐部的新成员早午餐会后来找我们
My parents will meet us up there after the new members' brunch at their club.
我爸盼着入会都盼了三年了
My father's been on the waiting list for three years.
记住 不管一路上发生了什么
Remember, no matter what happens on this ride
你已放弃"因某些人神经质对你造成束缚"而起诉我的权利
you've already waived your right to sue me for confining you with lunatics.
话说Jodie 你有在哪个俱乐部吗?
So, Jodie, do you belong to any clubs?
你可以选择不回应
You don't have to answer that.
我是法语俱乐部的主席
I'm president of the French Club,
学生会副主席 年鉴编辑
vice president of Student Council, editor of yearbook,
还在校网球队
and I'm also on the tennis team.
Daria 你怎么没在校网球队啊?
Daria, why aren't you on the tennis team?
因为其被归类为运动
Because it's classified as a sport.
说起来运动了 Jodie 你认识Kevin Thompson吗?
Speaking of sports, Jodie, do you know Kevin Thompson?
他和Daria一起做过科学实验来着
He and Daria did a science project together.
认识的 Kevin很棒的...
Oh, sure. Kevin's great...
擅长往自己脑袋里泼啤酒罐
at smashing beer cans with his head.
我真搞不懂为什么Daria不肯和他还有他朋友们多玩玩
I don't know why Daria doesn't hang around with him and his gang more.
和我睡觉不把脑袋塞进冰里是一个理由
For the same reason I don't sleep with my head packed in ice.
话说Jodie 有男朋友没?
So, Jodie, got a fella?
有的 他叫Michael
Yeah, his name's Michael.
不过大伙都叫他Mack
But everyone calls him Mack.
我们要去主楼吗?
Should we go to the main building,
还是去马棚申请临时工就行了?
or just apply for jobs in the stables?
我就跟Peter说"听着...
So I told Peter, "Look...
你才不管你约过我多少次 你就不是我的菜"
I don't care how many times you ask me out. You're not my type!"
了解 我都记不清他约过我多少次了
I know. I don't know how many times he's asked me out.
这话我刚说的
That's what I just said.
不 你刚说的是你才不管他约过你多少次
No, you said you don't care how many times he's asked you out.
可我就是说...
Well, I meant...
看啊 Quinn
Oh, look, Quinn.
她穿的凉鞋和你的同款
She's wearing sandals like yours.
这是重播么?
Is this a rerun?
我看不是 我去给你拿听健怡怎样?
I don't think so. Can I get you a diet soda?
不用 谢谢 不过你可以喝点葡萄汁
No, thanks. But help yourself to the grapes.
据说葡萄汁对皮疹有帮助
I hear they're good for breakouts.
嘿 姐 你看啥呢?
Hey, sis, what you watching?
换回来
Turn it back.
你俩小东西
You little geek.
嘿 怎么不看《时尚视野》了?
Hey, what happened to Fashion Vision?
抱歉哦 Quinn
Oh, sorry, Quinn.
要吃花生酱卷糖吗?
Um, you want a peanut butter log?
要换更好的杯子吗?
Need a smoother glass?
要我帮你解鞋带吗?
Should I fluff your shoelaces?
这个嘛...
Well, let's see...
你俩要是这么喜欢Quinn
If you guys like Quinn so much,
可以考虑收养她 然后我去和Morgendorffer一家生活
maybe you should adopt her and I can go live with the Morgendorffers.
- 赞 - 我去给你打包
- Cool. - I'll help you pack.
Quinn 这儿变得有点挤了呢
Quinn, it's getting kind of crowded in here.
Tiffany家应该宽敞些
Maybe Tiffany has more room.
这话什么意思 Sandi?
What do you mean, Sandi?
遇见新希望
你们好 欢迎来到格鲁夫希尔 我是Marina
Hello, welcome to Grove Hills. I'm Marina.
我是Jodie
I'm Jodie.
Daria
Daria.
Jodie Daria
Jodie, Daria.
请允许我介绍Lara Graham和Cassidy
I'd like you to meet Lara, Graham and Cassidy.
- 还好吗? - 很高兴认识你们
- What's up? - Hi, nice to meet you.
Lara 不如你给Jodie和Daria
Lara, why don't you fill Jodie and Daria
介绍下格鲁夫希尔式教育的诸多优势吧?
in on the many advantages of a Grove Hills education?
好的 优势一:
Well, number one:
你只需在这种冒牌聚会上才需要招徕声尖调高的招生员
you only have to put up with shrill recruiters at phony functions like this.
失陪下
Um, excuse me.
在这儿你不会像在家里一样...
And you're not surrounded by nearly as many stupid people
被那么多笨蛋包围
as you would be at home.
就比如说你爸妈吧
Starting with your parents.
或许这地方没那么烂呢
Maybe this place isn't so bad.
来格鲁夫希尔 你可以在宽敞的宿舍里冥思蒲鲁斯特
At Grove Hills, you can contemplate Proust in our spacious dorm rooms,
法国化学家
在美味的一饭之间与同学用拉丁语交谈
engage in conversation in Latin over a delicious meal...
从我们风景优美的钟楼上一跃跳河
Dump bodies into the river from our scenic bell tower.
不要犹豫 就是格鲁夫希尔 你的智慧之旅第一站
So all aboard to Grove Hills, your first station on the track to wisdom.
希望大伙都喜欢我们的小短片
I hope everyone enjoyed our little film.
很好
Great.
我想到一个很棒的开启本次欢迎会的方式
I think a super way to start this meet and greet session
大家来分享一下各自的人生目标
would be to tell a little about our goals in life.
谁愿意开个头呢?
Who'd like to start?
我希望有一天能拥有自己的公司
Well, someday I'd like to own my own business.
可能是个面向初创公司的咨询所吧
Maybe a consulting firm geared toward minority start-ups.
非常好 Daria 你的目标是什么呢?
Excellent! Daria? What about your goal?
那个 我没有诶...
Um, I don't have any.
来嘛 Daria
Oh, come, Daria.
你起码会有一个目标的
You must have some goal.
我的目标就是不要在40岁醒来时 痛苦地意识到
My goal is not to wake up at 40 with the bitter realization
我在一个恨之不及的岗位上浪费了一生
that I've wasted my life in a job I hate
就因为我在年少时被迫决定自己的事业方向
because I was forced to decide on a career in my teens.
欢迎来到格鲁夫希尔这座神圣殿堂
Welcome to the hallowed halls of Grove Hills.
诸位是否认为
Do you think it's a coincidence
富人与权贵之人相识只是巧合之事呢?
that the rich and powerful all seem to know each other?
再想想吧 他们在学校便已结识
Think again. They met at school.
别让您天赋异禀的子女沦落在公立学校的洪流中
Don't let your gifted progeny drown in the public school system.
说开来
After all.
您是希望他们更早地得到长春藤联盟的垂青?
Would you rather they get an early acceptance to the Ivy League,
还是停滞在三流大学的水平呢?
or stagnate at some third-rate college?
嘿 咱们母校诶
Hey! The old alma mater!
二位就是Jodie父母吧
You must be Jodie's parents.
为何这么说?
Why do you say that?
在下Andrew Landon 我爱人Michele
Andrew Landon. My wife, Michele.
嘿 Andrew
Hey, Andrew!
刚看你把豹牌汽车停那边了
Saw you parking your Jag out there.
送给自己的小礼物 庆祝成功抬高了摞层咖啡杯的装水量
A little gift I bought myself after hitting the big figures with my folding coffee cup.
要义在于一定不要让层与层之间的缝隙漏水
The key was finding a way to keep the damn creases from leaking.
话说 我曾经想到发明吸力助动的指甲剪呢
You know, I came up with the idea for the suction-powered nail clipper.
可谁料到被一哥们儿先发制人了
But then somebody beat me to the punch.
我小儿子Evan 中后卫的料 有没有?
My boy, Evan. A linebacker, huh?
不是说我不爱闺女 但Evan 他让我后继有人
Not that I don't love my girls, but Evan, he's my son.
Jodie跟我们说你的事了
Jodie told us all about you
为了要孩子 宁可放弃在美利坚世界的副主席高位
walking away from a senior vice presidency at U.S. World to have a baby!
真是勇气可嘉 很多女人...
That took guts. A lot of women...
够了 Evan确实是意外怀的
All right, so Evan wasn't planned.
但我不在乎
But I'm okay with it.
没准我能劝动Helen再要个儿子呢
Maybe I could talk Helen into having a boy.
没准我能劝动你离婚时把房分给我
Maybe I could talk you into letting me keep the house.
这张照片会不会显得我鼻子跟嘴靠太近了?
Does this picture make my nose look too close to my mouth?
没 它俩之间的距离蛮舒服的
No. They're a comfortable distance apart.
那我的牙呢?
How about my teeth?
门牙有点太白了 对不对?
The front ones aren't too white, are they?
没 它们的洁白程度再合适不过了
No, they have just the right amount of whiteness.
能去卡仕曼购物中心了吗?
Can we go to Cashman's now?
这身让我看起来胖吗?
Does this make me look fat?
没有的事
No way.
这身让我看起来胖吗?
Does this make me look fat?
不会
No!
这身让我看起来胖吗?
Does this make me look fat?
你特么压根不胖 好嘛?!
You're not freaking fat, okay?!
哎呀 我都说不完多喜欢Jodie了
No, I can't tell you how much I like Jodie.
真希望Daria和她人缘一样好
I just wish Daria were as popular.
既然Jodie交朋友都那么上手 Daria又怎会不行?
I mean, if Jodie can make friends so easily, why can't Daria?
Jodie交朋友为什么要不上手呢?
Why should Jodie have any problems making friends?
朗岱尔高中的少数民族学生比较少嘛
Well, there's not a lot of... diversity at Lawndale.
一小拨孩子的思想是很狭隘的 不会轻易接受...
A few people can be narrow-minded and not always accept
来自不同社会背景的"突如其来"的孩子
"right away" people from different backgrounds.
Jodie的社会背景跟Daria又有什么不同?
How is Jodie's background any different from Daria's?
你说得对
Absolutely right.
失陪下 我去趟洗手间
Excuse me while I... use the ladies room.
知道什么会惹毛我吗 Jake兄?
You know what riles me, Jake-o?
该死的福利骗局
Those damn welfare cheats.
其实我没...
Oh, well, I don't...
谢天谢地可以伪造帐目
Thank God for creative accounting,
不然我得花一半的家底养活那些好吃懒做的工人
or I'd be spending half my net supporting those couch potatoes.
是啊 但...
Yes, but...
全都因为假惺惺地禁止美国公司再雇佣童工
Because of those lousy cheats that American companies end up using child labor!
是啊 该死的福利骗局
Yeah... damn welfare cheats!
好了 Jake
Now, Jake.
许多兢兢业业的美国人偶尔还是需要一些帮助的
A lot of hard-working people just need a little help now and then.
福利政策没啥可吐槽的 对吧 Michele?
There's nothing wrong with that, right, Michele?
你凭什么觉得我会支持福利政策?
What makes you think I'm in favor of welfare?
好高兴你来我家玩的 Quinn
I'm so glad you're staying here, Quinn.
是呀 我也是
Yeah, me, too.
别和任何人说哦
Don't tell anybody this,
时尚俱乐部的人里面 我最喜欢你了
but I like you best out of everyone in the Fashion Club.
这话真贴心 Stacy
Um, that's nice, Stacy.
天啊 看Bridgett穿的吊带裙
God! Look at Bridgett in that slip dress.
吊带裙?
Slip dress?
其实吧 我想说你是我最好的朋友
In fact, I'd say you're my first-best friend.
Tiffany是我第二好的朋友
And Tiffany's my second-best friend.
Sandi是第三好的朋友
Sandi's my third-best friend.
有时候Tiffany会变成第三 Sandi变成第二
Although sometimes Tiffany's third and Sandi's second.
但你永远是最好的
But you're always first.
好吧 随便啦
Um, okay, whatever.
Quinn 你最喜欢谁呀?
Quinn, who do you like best?
Stacy 人家在读这篇打理睫毛的文章呢
Stacy! I'm trying to read this article on eyelashes.
对 抱歉
Oh, right, sorry.
不敢相信她居然穿这种东西
Ugh! I can't believe she's wearing it!
吊带裙太过时了吧
Slip dresses are so over!
就是 吊带裙太过时了
Yeah, slip dresses are so over.
话说Quinn 要不要去看电影?
So, Quinn, want to go to a movie?
好啊 你想看什么?
Sure. What do you want to see?
不知道 你想看什么就看什么咯
I don't know, whatever you want to see.
你穿了一身什么呀?
What are you wearing?
你想让我穿什么呀?
What do you want me to wear?
那又是什么?
And what's that?
我们可以做一个相同颜色的渐变染
I thought we could color our hair the same shade.
那个 我先走了
Um, I gotta go.
人们都说高中应该是人生中最快乐的时光
They say high school's supposed to be the happiest time of your life.
除非你的人生足够短
Only if your life is extremely short.
太对了 你很幽默
Exactly. You're funny.
给别人一次机会 大家是可以做朋友的吧?
See what happens when you give people a chance?
我们最快乐的时光应该是赚到第一个一百万
Our happiest years will begin when we make our first million.
真等不及一手搂一个大妞儿漫步在里维埃拉
I can't wait to stroll down the Riviera with a model on each arm.
南欧沿地中海一地区
天呐 那会有意思
Gee, that's interesting.
我觉得你虽然天赋异禀 但也可以道德败坏
I guess you can be intellectually gifted and still be morally bankrupt.
我求之不得呢
I certainly hope so.
天啊
Oh, my God.
不敢相信David还敢来这儿招摇
I can't believe David has the nerve to show up.
他以为他是谁啊?
Who does he think he is?
他怎么了? 考试作弊了吗?
What did he do? Cheat on a test?
更甚 我们今天拿到了能力测验成绩
Worse. We got our S.A.T. scores back today.
David只排到了90%的位次 白痴
David's were only in the 90th percentile. Idiot.
实在是没法跟他继续玩耍了
I just can't hang out with him anymore.
他太... 平庸了
He's too... banal.
过去他这个人非常有趣的
And he used to be so interesting.
感谢标准化测验的存在
Thank God for standardized tests.
不然你永远不知道谁是自己的真朋友
Otherwise you'd never know who your real friends are.
没错 我是说... 幽默
Right. I mean... amusing.
给别人一次机会 大家是可以做朋友的吧?
See what happens when you give people a chance?
Daria... 嘿大伙 等等
Daria...! Hey, guys, wait up.
你来干嘛?
What are you doing here?
我想借你电话用一下
Um, I need to use your phone.
你自己的电话不能用吗?
What's wrong with your phone?
能用 我能借宿一宿吗?
Nothing. Can I spend the night?
开玩笑嘛?
Are you kidding?
我妈说不许我一个人在家呆着
My mother says I can't stay home alone.
我保证不告密 甚至会帮你开酒桶
I won't say a word. I'll even spring for the keg,
不过剩下的打扫工作得你负责
but you have to pay for the dry cleaning.
现在才张罗派对 太晚了吧
It's too last-minute to throw a party.
那就煲一晚上电话粥呗
Then just talk on the phone all night.
问你朋友 如果可以变成一瓶指甲油
Ask your friends, if they could be a nail polish,
她们想变什么颜色 为什么
what color they would be and why.
我厌倦那套玩意了
I'm sick of that game.
恐怕你得回家了
You're afraid to go home.
才不要
I am not!
抱歉 没空床了
Sorry, no vacancies.
好啦 是我害怕啦
All right, I'm afraid!
家里有超大狗狗连环杀手什么的
There's mass serial puppy killers and stuff.
拜托 求你还不行嘛
Come on. Please?
我保证会后悔的
I'm going to regret this.
别介意 我已经后悔了
Never mind, I already do.
在格鲁夫希尔
Here at Grove Hills,
我们坚信 家长的参与至关重要
we strongly believe that parental involvement is imperative.
我也是非常赞同
I couldn't agree more.
作为格鲁夫希尔家长 诸位需要参加每月董事会议
As a Grove Hills parent, you'll be attending monthly board meetings,
周末大扫除派对 筹款启动会
weekend cleanup parties, fund-raising drives...
您在核计?
do you collate?
是啦
Um, sure.
我肯定会来 如果有时间 不过时间不多
I mean, I would if I had the time, which isn't often.
我会努力到场 日程允许的话
I'll try to be here, schedule permitting.
我比较关心 到底多少学生最后能上重点大学?
I was wondering, just how many students go on to top colleges?
91%
91 percent.
那剩余的这9%的学生要去向何处?
And what kind of schools do the other nine percent go to?
有些学生在完成格鲁夫希尔的学业后 需要休息
Well, some students require a bit of... rest after Grove Hills.
休息什么意思?
What kind of rest?
各位懂的
Oh, you know,
有时逃脱分数压力需要休息
some time away from the pressure of grades
逃脱竞争压力也需要休息
and away from the pressure of competition...
再有些时候 逃脱装扮压力挑食压力也需要休息
and occasionally away from the pressure of dressing and feeding themselves.
在来这儿之前 我是个流浪天才
Before I came here I was an intellectual outcast.
会因为引用Ayn Rand的话被嘲笑
They made fun of me for quoting Ayn Rand.
俄裔美国哲学家 小说家
我认为她令人烦倦的地方在于...
Actually, I think she's pretty disturbing...
这不是重点
That's not the point.
重点是你知道她是谁
The point is that you know who she is,
而在格鲁夫希尔 你可以和像我们这样的人讨论她
and that at Grove Hills, you can discuss her with people like us,
而不是一群废物白痴 或者什么四分卫
instead of idiots and fools and a quarterback
在全学校里瞎嚷嚷你裹着毛巾洗澡
who tells the whole school you shower in a towel.
我更愿见识写出有关毛泽东论文的四分卫
I'd like to see a quarterback write a paper on Mao.
我觉得文化大革命...
I think the Cultural Revolution is...
对于一个还没踏进这所学校的人 你话未免太多了点吧
You have an awful lot to say for someone who doesn't even go to this school yet.
你这话什么意思?
What's that supposed to mean?
我说 为什么不先看看你能不能进格鲁夫希尔
It means why don't we see whether you get in to Grove Hills
我们再开始听你扯长篇大论?
before we start listening to your opinions.
别因为某个运动员让你觉得自己像个衰货
Just because some jock made you feel like the loser you are,
就把怒气撒我身上
don't take it out on me.
我才不是衰货 我智商165
I'm not a loser! I have a 165 I.Q.!
谁管你啊? 还不是一样的无聊悲催
Who cares? You're still boring and miserable!
别一天到晚把脑袋当屁股用
Try taking your head out of your butt for once
睁开你那双小近视眼好好看看
and opening up your myopic little eyes.
或者你165的智商是不是应该聪明到直接看出自己什么货色?
Or doesn't your 165 I.Q. make you smart enough to see the way you really are?
我保证你这辈子别想再进这所学校
I'll make sure you never set foot in this school again!
松了口气
That's a relief.
我还以为你要威胁我们呢
For a minute there I thought you were going to threaten us.
认了吧 感觉爽爆了
Admit it. That felt good.
有点啦 好吧 爽爆了
Well, a little. Okay, a lot.
挫Graham那样的混蛋可是生活的一大乐趣呢
Busting on jerks like Graham is one of life's few pleasures.
你应该多挫挫才是
You should try it more often.
快别扯了
Oh, shut up.
上手真快
Um, good start.
你知道自己一贯的消极作风是一种自卫 对吗?
You realize your negative approach to everything is self-defeating, right?
好吧 拿毒舌战胜别人感觉还不错
Well, it's nice to know there's someone I can defeat.
我是说 挫了别人 你自己的痛苦可能减轻了
I mean, you may spare yourself some pain by cutting everyone off,
但同时你也失去了很多好的东西
but you miss out on a lot of good stuff, too.
听着 Jodie
Look, Jodie,
我太聪明太敏感了
I'm too smart and too sensitive
没法和这样一个世界 这样一个时代 这样一个我妹共处
to live in a world like ours at a time like this with a sister like mine.
或许我确实错过了某些好东西 但这态度对我就是有效
Maybe I do miss out on stuff, but this attitude is what works for me now.
那你就应该理解什么态度对我有效
Then you'll understand what works for me now.
在家 我是Jodie
At home, I'm Jodie.
我可以随心所欲畅所欲言
I can say or do whatever feels right.
但在学校 我是出众的黑人女同学
But at school, I'm the Queen of the Negroes.
是完美的非裔美国少年
The perfect African-American teen.
是朗岱尔所有非裔美国少年的行为榜样
The role model for all of the other African-American teens at Lawndale.
他们别被我带坏呀
Oups! Where'd they go?
相信我 我更想像你一样生活
Believe me, I'd like to be more like you.
好吧 我也得承认 有些时候我也希望自己能像你一样
Well, I have to admit, there are times when I'd like to be more like you.
真的?
Really?
我只是说某些时候
I'm not saying all the time.
那朗岱尔还是格鲁夫希尔?
So, Lawndale or Grove Hills?
我还是选朗岱尔吧
I'm sticking with Lawndale.
来了这儿 我会被牛肉汉堡里的馅料毒死的
If I came here, I'd end up poisoning the sloppy joe mix.
是啊 你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
我马上就能成为朗岱尔优秀学生代表了
I'm pushed to the breaking point being Miss Model Student at Lawndale.
在这待一年非死不可
A year here might kill me.
我是说他确实挺好挺萌的
I mean, he was really nice and cute and stuff
但他只比我高五公分诶
but he was only two inches taller than me,
可我所有的鞋子
and my entire shoe collection
都只适合跟比我高七公分的男孩约会时穿
is based on the concept of dating guys three inches taller than me or more.
我不懂抽象艺术
I don't get abstract art.
谁会愿意看一群唧唧歪歪的六眼怪啊
Who wants to look at a bunch of squiggly six-eyed people
人家在购物网上轻轻松松就能买到漂亮写实的猫咪油画
when you can get those really pretty cat paintings on the shopping network?
不是说我不想在艺术上浪费钱
Not that I would ever waste money on art.
嘿 Janey 借点钱有吗?
Hey, Janey. You got any money?
钱? 你要出去吗?
Money? Are you going out?
我不介意出去兜兜风哦
I wouldn't mind going out for a while.
当然了 我不知道要不要和一个如此装扮的家伙出门
Of course, I don't know if I'd want to go out with someone dressed like that.
你谁啊?
Uh, who are you?
记得Quinn吗? Daria她妹
You remember Quinn, Daria's sister?
想起来了 Daria她妹 嘿
Oh, yeah. Daria's sister. Hey.
拜托 我有名字好吧
Excuse me, I have a name.
知道 Daria她妹嘛
Right. Daria's sister.
你还是希望他能回来?
You mean you want him back?
就算他把你绑在椅子上
Even though he tied you to a chair
扔到车水马龙的八道高速路中间?
and left it on an eight-lane highway in the middle of rush hour?
他当时只是失心疯了
He got carried away by the moment.
她怎么能穿成这样就上电视?
How can she go on TV looking like that?
你真的确定不想去格鲁夫希尔中学嘛?
So you're sure you don't want to go to Grove Hills?
绝对的
Positive.
干嘛要去一个特殊学校学一无是处的东西
Why go to a special school to learn useless information
反正我在朗岱尔也能免费学
when I can do it at Lawndale for free?
可是Daria 爸爸和我都觉得你这样是错过了一个重要的机遇
Well, Daria, your father and I think you're passing up an important opportunity.
但你说...
But you said...
不过呢 我们说过会尊重你的决定 我们必须信守承诺
However, we said we'd respect your decision, and a promise is a promise.
真的? 那你答应给我买小马咯?
Really? So I can have that pony now?
要是你改变主意 随时可以告诉我们 好的吧?
If you change your mind, sweetie, you just let us know, all right?
顺便 你们觉得Landon一家怎么样?
By the way, what did you think of the Landons?
- 特别好 - 没错 特好 特别好
- Very nice! - Yes, very nice, very nice.
你们惹着人家了
You ticked them off.
没没没没
No, no, no, no.
是
Yes.
你当然不一定非要去格鲁夫希尔
Of course you don't have to go to Grove Hills.
我绝不会要求你做让你后悔的事
I'd never ask you to do anything you'd regret.
我也是
Oh... me neither.
话说 你们觉得Morgendorffer一家怎么样?
So, what do you think of the Morgendorffers?
真是脑袋被门夹的一对
What a couple of head cases.
抵押贷款之家 亲爱的抵押贷款家
Mortgage, sweet mortgage!
你现在想做点啥 亲爱的?
What do you want to do now, honey?
临时分居?
Trial separation?
这就又说到别的事了
And then the other thing is,
到底谁想到"块块手链"这蠢名字的?
who came up with the name "tennis bracelet" anyway?
听起来就像防汗带 要我说的话
It sounds like some kind of a sweatband, if you ask me.
猜我会起什么名?
You know what I'd name them?
腕饰
Wrist ornaments.
就像树木挂饰一样 只是放手腕
It's like a tree ornament, only for your wrist.
听起来很喜庆吧?
Doesn't that sound festive?
快... 带她... 走
Take... her... now.
你俩怎么跑一块去的
This story I've gotta hear.
我要写到手软
租个脑子吧
Rent a brain.
《如何赢得友情以德服人》
How to Win Friends and Influence People.
还不错
It's not bad.
讲的都是好态度能为你赢得的东西
It's about all the things a good attitude can get you.
我这本也是讲态度的
This is about attitude as well.
黑暗之心 (波兰裔英国作家约瑟夫·康拉德所著小说)
"年轻人深入未知疆域之旅
"A young man's journey into unknown territory
和灵魂深处的野蛮暴行面对面"
brings him face-to-face with the savage brutality within his own soul."
欢迎微博关注
@漫迪字幕组